A Finding Aid to the William P. Daley Papers, 1905-2004 (bulk 1951-2001), in the Archives of American Art AAA.dalewill
Archives of American Art
- Teaching Files, 1951-1998, undated; Series 7; 1.3 Linear feet Boxes 9-10
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Proposed Senior Project and Craft Curriculum, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Ceramic Studio Residence Program, 1989, 1995, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Craft Department Self Study, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Semester Grades, 1973-1990, undated (Box 10, Folder 8-10)
  - General Notes on Teaching Art and Ceramics, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence About Teaching Positions, 1956, 1963-1978, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Teaching Contracts, 1961-1989 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Dismantled Ceramics Notebook, circa 1968-1998 (Box 10, Folder 14-22)
  - "Ceramic Shop Notes", 1969 (Box 10, Folder 23-24)
  - Kiln Instructions, 1980, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Artist Files, 1938-2001, undated; Series 8; 2.1 Linear feet Boxes 10-12
  This series contains files for artists who were colleagues or friends of William Daley, and may include announcements and invitations to the artist's exhibitions, correspondence with Daley, biographical material such as resumes, printed material, and photographs of the artist. Correspondence between Daley and the artists include incoming letters, postcards, and drafts of outgoing letters. Many of the artists were either Daley's students or co-workers, and most of the files contain material spanning ten years or more. Also found is a transcribed interview William Daley conducted of artist Viktor Schrekengost in 1996. Materials in this series are arranged alphabetical by artist's last name.
  - Andrade, Edna, 1983, 1993-1997 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Arneson, Robert, 1979-1996 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Autio, Rudy, 1980-1996 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Bae, Jin Hwan, 1990, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Black, Harding, 1990-1994 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Bodine, Sarah and Michael Dunas, 1987, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bonner, Jonathan, 1989-1993 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Bonovitz, Jill, 1989-1998, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Boughner, Cynthia, 1994-1996 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Brady, Robert, 1981-1995 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Bouillard, William, 1990, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Bunker, George, 1965, 1986-1993 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Carreiro, Joseph, 1957, 1978, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Chappelle, Robert, 1985-1996, undated (Box 11, Folder 9-10)
  - Chihuly, Dale, 1978-1990 (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
  - Cho, Chung Hyun, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Church, Sharon, 1990, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Colker, Ed, 1985-1994 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Cushing, Val, 1970-1984, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Dailey, Dan, 1978-1998, undated (Box 11, Folder 17-18)
  - DeVore, Richard, 1975-1997, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Doran, Patricia, 1990-1996, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Duckworth, Ruth, 1977-1993 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Duryea, Lynn, 1990-1998, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Eberle, Edward, 1978-1997 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Erlebacher, Walter, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Ferguson, Ken, 1981-1999 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Flexer, Mindy, 1986, 1992, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Frey, Viola, 1981-1992 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Gill, John, 1982-1998 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Glick, John, 1979-1997, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Goodman, Sidney, 1975-1996 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Greenamyer, George, 1980-1998, undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Harvey, Rebecca, 1993-1996 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Hepburn, Tony, 1980-1991, undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Higby, Wayne, 1973-1997 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Holzapfel, Michelle, 1991-1993 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Howard, Robert, 1981-1998 (Box 11, Folder 36-37)
  - Hsu, Chia-sueih, 1988-1997, undated (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Jaffe, Jeanne, 1989, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Karros, Alec, 1983-2001, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Kuo, Yih-Wen, 1990-1997 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Levine, Marilyn, 1979-1991 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Marks, Graham, 1977-1995, undated (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
  - Martin, Stephen, 1984, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Mayo, Noel, 1993, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Metzker, Ray, 1981-1990 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Naples, Lisa, 1986-1999 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Neff, Edith, 1979-1992 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Ottenberg, Perry, 1982, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Owens-Hart, Winnie, 1979, 1987-1997 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Pewabic Pottery, 1986-1989, 1993, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Piper, Jane, 1976-1990, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Reinhardt, Richard, 1969, 1974, 1984-1999, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Roehm, Mary, 1987, 1994-1998 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Salomon, Judith, 1988, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Schreckengost, Viktor, 1979-1997, undated (Box 12, Folder 19-20)
  - Seelig, Warren, 1983-1998 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Shin, Sang-ho, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Simoncelli, Chris, 1985, 1990-1995 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Staffel, Rudolf, 1966-1996 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Staley, Chris, 1982-1993, undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Stephenson, John and Susanne, 1978-2001, undated (Box 12, Folder 26-27)
  - Stewart, Lizbeth, 1979-1991, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Takaezu, Toshiko, 1990-1998, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Troy, Jack, 1983-1998, undated; (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 30-31)
  - Turner, Robert, 1979-1996, undated (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Vaskys, Petras, 1984, 1986, 1997, undated (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Vavrek, Ken, 1982-1994, undated (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Voulkos, Peter, 1952, 1976-1993, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Winokur, Paula and Robert, 1976-1992 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Woell, J. Fred, 1994-1998 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Woodman, Betty, 1977-1994 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Wright, David, 1989-1998, undated (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Wyman, William, 1978-1980 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Zaeder, Thayer, 1986-1993 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Zeisel, Eva, 1992, undated (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous, A-M, 1985-2000, undated (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous, N-Z, 1938, 1984-1994, undated (Box 12, Folder 44)
- Reference Files, 1951-2001, undated; Series 9; 1 Linear feet Box 13; (Box 13; 1.0 linear foot)
  This series contains material on a variety of topics that William Daley compiled as reference files for projects and teaching. This includes files on the art of various countries, in the form of postcards, maps, and guidebooks, as well as files of numerous published or handwritten formulas, tables, and directions for using ceramic or other sculptural materials. Also found are materials on art, craft, and education, and other general subjects in the form of photocopies or clippings of articles. These files also include teaching materials written and originally used by others. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Africa, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Animals and Nature, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Architecture, 1984, undated (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  - Art Censorship, 1990-1992 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Art Education, 1953, 1983-1998, undated (Box 13, Folder 6-8)
  - Art Essays, 1973-1994, undated (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
  - The Brain, 1995-2000 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Ceramic History, 1988-1992, undated (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
  - Ceramics Technical Notebook, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Ceramic Toxicology, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - China, 1980, 1990, undated (Box 13, Folder 16-17)
  - Clay Bodies and Mixing Slips, 1968-1980, undated (Box 13, Folder 18-19)
  - Clay Materials: Technical Analysis, 1967-1977, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Craft Philosophy, 1967, 1986-2001, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Earthenware, 1977, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Ecology, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Education, 1995, 2000, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - England, circa 1986, undated (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - France, undated (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Frank Lloyd Wright Designs, undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Frit and Feldspar Analysis Tables, 1968, undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Geometry, 1953, 1982, undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Glazes, undated (Box 13, Folder 30-31)
  - Indian Art, 1982, undated (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Islamic Art, undated (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Japan, 1954, 1968, undated (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Korean Art, 1988, undated (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Masonry, undated (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Metal Techniques, 1968, undated (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Molecular Aspects of Ceramic Materials, undated (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Moravian Tile Works/Henry Chapman Mercer, 1966, 1979-1991, undated (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Native American Art, 1980, 1982, undated (Box 13, Folder 40-41)
  - New Clay Body, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Pickett Collection, 1985, undated (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Plaster Mixing, undated (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Quotes and Ideas for Future Essays, 1991, undated (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Raku Glazes, 1968, 1980, undated (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - South America, undated (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Statements on Art by Artists, 1951, 1981-1991, undated (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Terra Sigillata Composition, undated (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Word Processors, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 50)
- Printed Material, 1936-2004, undated; Series 10; 1.9 Linear feet Boxes 14-15
  This series houses printed material and publications including newspaper and magazine clippings on Daley, Helen Drutt Gallery, and ceramics in general. Files of clippings about Daley contain many reviews of his work. Also within this series are numerous exhibition announcements and invitations. These are arranged by medium and chronologically under each heading, with separate folders for the galleries from which Daley received a large amount of material. This series contains exhibition catalogs primarily from the National Ceramic Exhibition (later called The Ceramic National), and various copies of journals and newsletters on the topic of ceramics. Also found are manuals on ceramics, miscellaneous published essays, brochures, and art postcards.
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Architectural Ceramics, 1974-1992, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Ceramics, 1978-1999, undated (Box 14, Folder 2-9)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Fiber, 1962, 1978-1997 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Glass, 1979-1998, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Metal, 1985-1998, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Painting, 1973-1999, undated (Box 14, Folder 13-15)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Printmaking, 1983-1997, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Wood, 1979-1998, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Braunstein/Quay Gallery, 1980-1993 (Box 14, Folder 18-19)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Exhibit A, 1973-1984, undated (Box 14, Folder 20-21)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Garth Clark Gallery, 1981-1997 (Box 14, Folder 22-27)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Helen Drutt Gallery, 1974-1998, undated (Box 14, Folder 28-31)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Miscellaneous, 1981-1998, undated (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, William Daley, 1951-1976, 1979-1998, undated (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Clippings, Helen Drutt Gallery, 1975-1990, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, Ceramics, 1938, 1940, 1966-1995, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, National Ceramic Exhibition, 1936, 1937, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, National Ceramic Exhibition, 1940, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, The Ceramic National, 1958-1959, 1962-1966, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Miscellaneous, 1957-1970, 1983-1997, undated (Box 15, Folder 9-10)
  - American Craft Museum News, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Arts & Crafts, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Ceramic Arts Newsletter, 1983-1984, 1986, 1988-1997 (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
  - Ceramic Arts Notes, 1993, 1994, 1996, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Ceramic Industry, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Ceramics Monthly, 1954-1956 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Ceramophile, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Clay Talks: Reflections by American Master Ceramicists, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Craft Horizons, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - NCECA Newsletter, 1980-1981, 1985, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - The Shards Newsletter, 1980-1982 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Newsletters and Journals, 1959, 1980-2001, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Manuals, Glazes by Charles Abbott, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Manuals, The Use of Iowa Clays in Small-Scale Production of Ceramic Art by Paul E. Cox, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Manuals, Kansas Volcanic Ash Resources, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Manuals, An Elementary Survey of Ceramic Processes, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Manuals, Glaze Calculation by Steven A. Goldberg, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 28-29)
  - Manuals, Fabrication of Plexiglas, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - New Brunswick Drawing Course Graded Practice Books by H. H. Hagerman, M.A., undated (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - A New Method of Assisting the Invention in Drawing Original Compositions of Landscape by Alexander Cozens, undated (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - "The Music of Poetry," by T. S. Eliot, undated (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Published Essays by Others, undated (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - University of the Arts Brochures and Programs, 1987-1995, undated (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Art Museum and Gallery Brochures, 1990-1992, undated (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Duplicates of Published Writings by Daley, 1991, undated (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Directions for "The Hat Trick", undated (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Art Postcards, undated (Box 15, Folder 39-42)
  - Train Postcards, undated (Box 15, Folder 43)
- Photographs, 1953-1992, undated; Series 11; 5 Folders Box 15
  This series contains photographs of William Daley throughout his career. The majority of the photographs depict Daley teaching and interacting with his students. Also included are photographs of the artist with his family, and early portraits of Daley working in his studio. There are also photographs of artwork by others ranging from outdoor sculpture to student work, and one file for unidentified photographs. Note that photographs related to certain events or artists may also be found in series 3, 4, 5 and 8.
  - William Daley and Family, 1984-1990, undated (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Daley at Work, 1955-1964, undated (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Class Photographs, 1953, undated (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Artwork by Others, 1971, 1989, 1992, undated (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 15, Folder 48)
- Financial Files, 1962-1997, undated; Series 12; 4 Folders Box 16
  This series consists of various bills, receipts, and expense lists. Also found is a list of pot sales for 1988 and a cash book containing expense lists for projects William Daley completed during the mid-1960s.
  - Cash Book, 1962-1966 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Pot Sales, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970, 1986-1997, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Artwork, 1954-2003, undated; Series 13; 3 Folders Boxes 15-16
  The series consists of drawings and sketches by William Daley, including one file of eight original sketches for unidentified projects. Also found are two oversize files of signed copies made in 2003 of drawings done throughout Daley's career. This includes drawing studies for projects, compositions based on ceramic works, such as "Body Pot Revisited," and miscellaneous drawings such as "John Pickett in Hospital - Stroke" and a 1964 self-portrait. Items are arranged chronologically within each file.
  - Drawings, 1954-2003, undated (Box 15, Folder 49-50)
  - Sketches, 1968-1972, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)